A Guide to the Metropolitan Economic Development Council Archives
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Metropolitan Economic Development Council Archives 1977-1983, n.d.
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 270
13.5 linear feet
Metropolitan Economic Development Council Archives
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions
Acquisition Information
Donated to the Special Collections and Archives by the Executive Director of the Metropolitan Economic Development Council in August 1989 by Deed of Gift.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Metropolitan Economic Development Council (MEDC) was formed in 1978 as a way to attract companies to the Richmond area.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence with various company personnel, publicity for area companies, advertising, speeches, magazine and newspaper articles, and newsletters. Includes information on the American Economic Development Council, Executive Women International, American Industrial Development Council, Industrial Development Authority, and local companies.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Materials are arranged chronologically or alphabetically.
Organization
The collection is organized in three series: Correspondence arranged by date, Correspondence arranged alphabetically, and subject files.
Contents List
- Correspondence 1979-1983
  Arranged chronologically by date.
  - July 1979-June 1980, 12 files (Box 1)
  - July 1981-June 1983, 25 files (Box 2)
- Correspondence 1980-1983
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - A-E, 12 files (Box 3)
  - F-N, 13 files (Box 4)
  - O-Y, 17 files (Box 5)
- Subject files 1977-1983
  - Action Report Publication 1979-1981 (Box-folder 6:1-2)
  - Advertising 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Advertising Committee 1981-1983 (Box-folder 6:4-5)
  - Advertising General Correspondence 1979-1983 (Box-folder 6:6-8)
  - American Economic Development Council (AEDC) 1980-1983 (Box-folder 6:9-10)
  - AEDC Newsletters 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6:11)
  - American Industrial Develpment Council (AIDC) 1977-1980 (Box-folder 6:12)
  - AIDC Journal 1980 (Box-folder 6:13)
  - AIDC Newsletter 1980-1981 (Box-folder 6:14)
  - AIDC Newsletter Legislative Affairs 1978-1980 (Box-folder 6:15)
  - AIPR Indrop Publishing Co., Inc. 1979-1980 (Box-folder 6:16-17)
  - Airport Blue Ribbon 1980-1981 (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Ambassador Steering Commiittee 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6:19)
  - Ambassadors 1980-1983 (Box-folder 6:20-21)
  - Ambassador Contracts (Box-folder 6:22)
  - Ambassadors Luncheon 1980 (Box-folder 6:23)
  - Ambassadors @Questionnaires 1981-1982 (Box-folder 6:24)
  - Area Development Magazine 1982 (Box-folder 6:25)
  - Auditors 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6:26)
  - Auditors: Gary, Walls, and Col. 7-1-81-6-30-82 (Box-folder 6:27)
  - Auditors: Gary, Stosch, Walls and Co. (Richard L. George) 1979-1980 (Box-folder 6:28)
  - Auditors: Peat, Marwick, Mitchell and Co. 1979-1980 (Box-folder 6:29)
  - AC 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6:30)
  - Aviation 1980-1983 (Box-folder 6:31-33)
  - Awards 1982 (Box-folder 6:34)
  - Board of Directors Minutes 1979-1982 (Box-folder 7:1-3)
  - Board of Directors Miscellaneous 1979-1983 (Box-folder 7:4-6)
  - Budget 1982-1983 (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Budget Formula Review Committee 1981 (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Budget Information 1981-1983 (Box-folder 7:9)
  - Business Reply Cards Returned (Box-folder 7:10)
  - Certified Development Co. (Box-folder 7:11)
  - CETA 1979-1980 (Box-folder 7:12)
  - Chamber Industrial Study 1979 (Box-folder 7:13)
  - Chamber and MEDC Inter-office Correspondence 1982 (Box-folder 7:14)
  - Chamber and MEDC Inter-office Memos 1979-1982 (Box-folder 7:15-16)
  - Chamber Research Committee 1979 (Box-folder 7:17)
  - Chamber of Commerce Economic Development Council 1979-1980 (Box-folder 7:18)
  - Chesterfield County 1981-1983 (Box-folder 7:19-20)
  - Chesterfield-Miscellaneous 1978-1980 (Box-folder 7:21)
  - Chris Wood 1978-1982 (Box-folder 7:22)
  - City of Richmond 1981-1983 (Box-folder 7:23-24)
  - City of Richmond-Miscellaneous 1979-1980 (Box-folder 7:25)
  - City Venture Co. 1981 (Box-folder 7:26)
  - Coastal Plans Regional Commission-Virginia Division 1979 (Box-folder 7:27)
  - Consultants 1978-1981 (Box-folder 7:28)
  - Conway Publications 1980-1983 (Box-folder 7:29-30)
  - Coors Brewery 1972 (Box-folder 7:31)
    Memos to Carlton P. Moffatt, Jr.
  - Economic Development Chamber of Commerce 1981-1982 (Box-folder 7:32)
  - Economic Development Council-Metro Area 1976-1979 (Box-folder 7:33)
  - Electronic Business January 1983 (Box-folder 7:34)
  - Employment Applications 1981-1983 (Box-folder 7:35)
  - Executive Newsletter 1979-1981 (Box-folder 7:36)
  - Executive Women International (EWI) 1981-1984 (Box-folder 7:37-43)
  - EWI Board Minutes 1983 (Box-folder 8:1)
  - EWI Gnereral Information Publications 1983-1984 (Box-folder 8:2)
  - EQI Pulbic Relations 1983 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Executour 1982-1983 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Executour #1 1979-1981 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Executour#2 1981 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Executour 1982 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Facts: About the Richmond Area (book) 1969-1980 (Box-folder 8:8)
  - Finnegan and Agee 1983 (Box-folder 8:9)
  - Finnegan and Agee Advertising Agency 1979-1981 (Box-folder 8:10-11)
  - Foreign Trade Zones 1981-1983 (Box-folder 8:12)
  - Hanson, Russell G. Sr. 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8:13-14)
  - Hanover 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8:15)
  - Hanover County 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8:16)
  - Hanover Miscellaneous 1979-1980 (Box-folder 8:17)
  - Henrico County 1982-1983 (Box-folder 8:18-19)
  - Henrico County 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8:20)
    IDA dinner meeting included
  - Henrico County Miscellaneous 1979-1980 (Box-folder 8:21)
  - I-95 1978-1979 (Box-folder 8:22)
  - Inc. 1981 (Box-folder 8:23)
  - Industrial Development Authority 1979-1982 (Box-folder 8:24-26)
  - Industrial Development Magazine Reports 1980-1981 (Box-folder 8:27-28)
  - Industry Week 1979 (Box-folder 8:29)
  - Interbake Foods, Inc. 1975-1981 (Box-folder 8:30)
  - Invest in America's Cities-Zurich, Switzerland 1981 (Box-folder 8:31)
  - Kellerco 1983 (Box-folder 8:32)
  - Labor Information 1980 (Box-folder 8:33)
  - Labor Market Trends 1979-1980 (Box-folder 8:34)
  - Labor Market Trends 1980 (Box-folder 8:35)
    Chronological file
  - Long Range Planning Committee 1979-1981 (Box-folder 8:36)
  - Miscellaneous 1978-1982 (Box-folder 9:1-10)
  - Miscellaneous Reports 1981-1983 (Box-folder 9:11)
  - National Real Estate Investor 1980 (Box-folder 9:12)
  - New and Expanding Industry Reports and Miscellaneous Correspondence 1977 (Box-folder 9:13)
  - News Articles and Publicity 1979-1983 (Box-folder 9:14-16)
  - News Releases 1978-1983 (Box-folder 9:17-18)
  - Office Furniture and Fixtures 1979 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - Operating Committee Minutes 1979-1983 (Box-folder 9:20)
  - Operating Committee Miscellaneous 1979-1983 (Box-folder 9:21-23)
  - Philadelphia, PA Trip May 12-16, 1982 (Box-folder 10:1)
  - Poll Operating Committee 1983 (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Private Industry Council 1979-1981 (Box-folder 10:3-4)
  - "Profits" Magazine published by Bank of Virginia 1979 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Program of Action (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Publications and Correspondence 1982-193 (Box-folder 10:7)
  - Publications Subscriptions 1979-1980 (Box-folder 10:8-9)
  - Publicity 1979-1981 (Box-folder 10:10-12)
  - Research Committee 1982 (Box-folder 10:13)
  - Resumes (Box-folder 10:14-15)
  - "Richmond Day in Washington" 1982 (Box-folder 10:16-18)
  - Richmond Regional Planning District Commission 1979-1980 (Box-folder 10:19-20)
  - Safeguard Systems (Box-folder 10:21)
  - Salary and Benefit Review Committee 1983 (Box-folder 10:22)
  - Sewer Treatment Committee State Water Board 1980 (Box-folder 10:23)
  - Southern Industrial Development Council (SIDC) 1979-1983 (Box-folder 10:24-26)
  - Southeastern Community Development Association 1980 (Box-folder 10:27)
  - Southeastern Community Development Association (Box-folder 10:28)
  - Speeches 1979-1983 (Box-folder 10:29-30)
  - Stone and Weber Management Consultants, New York 1978-1979 (Box-folder 10:31)
  - Standards and Poor's Register 1978 (Box-folder 10:32)
  - Target Industry Study Project 1981 (Box-folder 10:33)
  - VDID Tour of the Metropolitan Richmond Area December 16, 1982 1982-1983 (Box-folder 10:34)
  - VEPCO Economic Development Association 1982 (Box-folder 10:35-36)
  - Virginia Economic Development Association 1982 (Box-folder 10:37)
  - Virginia Industrial Development 1979 (Box-folder 10:38)
  - Virginia Industrial Professionals 1981 (Box-folder 10:39)
  - Virginia State chamber of Commerce 1981-1982 (Box-folder 10:40-41)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce Industrical Development Commission 1982 (Box-folder 10:42)
  - Wall Street Journal Ad (Block Ad by Richmond Business) 1979 (Box-folder 10:43)